insidebrucrewlife.com 2019-04-18

# Privacy Policy - Inside BruCrew Life

## **PRIVACY POLICY**

Privacy Policy for Inside BruCrew Life updated on May 2, 2018.

The privacy of our visitors at Inside BruCrew Life is very important to us.  We value and protect your privacy.

We may change this Policy from time to time, so please check this page occasionally to ensure that you are happy with any changes. By using our website, you are agreeing to be bound by this Policy.

If you have any questions regarding this Policy and our privacy practices, please email Jocelyn at insidebrucrewlife@gmail.com

At Inside BruCrew Life, the privacy of our guests is of utmost importance to us. This privacy policy outlines the type of personal information that is received and collected on our site and how it is used. We recognize that the privacy of your personal information is important. Here is information on what types of personal information we receive and collect when you use and visit Inside BruCrew Life, and how we safeguard your information.  We will never sell your personal information to third parties.

##  **Who is Inside BruCrew Life?**

Inside BruCrew Life was started in the fall of 2008 by Jocelyn Brubaker. We are a husband and wife team sharing recipes and life stories for you and your family.

##  **How We collect Information from You:**

 **Log Files**  
As with most other websites, we collect and use the data contained in log files.  The information in the log files include your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP (internet service provider, such as AOL), the browser you used to visit our site (such as Internet Explorer or Firefox), the time you visited our site and which pages you visited throughout our site.

 **Cookies and Web Beacons**  
We do use cookies to store information, such as your personal preferences when you visit our site.  This could include only showing you a popup once in your visit, or the ability to login to some of our features, such as forums.

We also use third party advertisements on Inside BruCrew Life to support our site.  Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP, the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed.  This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites).

You can chose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security.  However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites.  This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts.

##  **What Personal Data We Collect and Why We Collect It:**

 **Comments:**

Here at Inside BruCrew Life we love hearing from our readers who have tried our recipes, have questions, or want to know more. We do this through the option of comments.

To leave a comment you may leave it anonymously or leave a name, email address, website, and comment.

We only use this information to identify you as the comment maker and will never pass this on to any third party.

Your email address will never be shown in the comment section of the site.

Your details will remain in the database unless we remove it or the article is removed from the site.

You may request that we delete the comment and remove your details at any time. Please email Jocelyn at insidebrucrewlife@gmail.com to request any removals.

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

 **Email Subscribers:**

If you choose to join one of our regular newsletters, then your email address is required so that you can be sent the emails.

Your data is collected by our Email Service Provider [Mad Mimi](https://madmimi.com/).

You may unsubscribe at any time from our newsletters using the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the email, or you can email Jocelyn at insidebrucrewlife@gmail.com and ask to be removed. _Please make sure that you are using the same email address that you receive the emails from to do this._

Within the Email Service Provider we use tags to track the pages that you visit and actions that you take within the emails, so that we can provide a more personalized email service to you.

We send emails a few times each week and with our tracking try to make these as relevant to you as possible.

Details that we hold including your name, email address and where you have visited will never be passed onto a Third Party.

 **If You are Under 16:**

This page does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. If a parent or guardian believes we may have information in our database, please contact Jocelyn at insidebrucrewlife@gmail.com immediately, and we will do our best to find and remove this information.

Please obtain your parent’s permission before entering any personal information on Inside BruCrew Life, as we are very concerned with your privacy as well.

##  **Advertising on Inside BruCrew Life:**

We use third party advertisements on Inside BruCrew Life to support our site.

  * Google Affiliates
  * Mediavine

Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP, the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed.

This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites).

##  **How and Why We Track your Visit:**

Like most websites around the world we use Google Analytics (GA) to process information about the number of visitors on our site and their behavior.

We use this information to record the number of people visiting Inside BruCrew Life, to better understand where you discover our site, (from social media, google or another site) how you use it, and to see how people move throughout the site.

GA records your approximate location down to town level, the type device you are using e.g. Mobile or Table, Name of device e.g. iPad or Samsung Galazy etc…, operating system e.g. Windows 10 or iOS and browser e.g. Firefox or Chrome none of this data can be used to identify you.

Google does record your IP address. However, we do not have access to this information, and it modifies it so that you can not be identified. Only the area that you are in is recorded.

 **Google Analytics and Demographics:**

We are committed to ensuring that our website contains content that is valuable and useful to our readers.

To help us with this we have implemented the Google analytics demographics and interest reporting features on our website. These tools allow us to review anonymous data regarding the gender, age and interests of website visitors and adapt our website content to better reflect their needs.

Although this information is collected through your Google ad settings, it is not provided to us in a personally-identifiable format. This means we cannot identify what information is about you, and we will not try to figure it out. You can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customise Google Display Network ads using the [Google Ad settings](https://adssettings.google.ca/anonymous?sig=ACi0TCim925cB07-7cpwU1t82Zih-cyZJ-z258Rhs2_ob_VD9-KN0PF7SNjosxPqWAnMkL5o3KkIzcaiKhInpLNrtrjGb3FOZ2AF3COImtlEVfU_oOnno0I&hl=en) or through the [Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/). To do this Google Analytics uses a “cookie” on your machine.

 **Cookies:**

These are little pieces of code that we use to track your use of our site and to provide the best possible experience for you.

Specifically we use them for:

  * Our commenting system so that you do not have to always enter your details
  * Collecting data as part of Google Analytics so that we can see who has visited our website

You can choose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing your preferences in your browser.

However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites. This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts.

  * Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on www.insidebrucrewlife.com
  * Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to Inside BruCrew Life and other sites on the Internet.
  * You may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL – <https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads>

## **How Long We Retain Your Data:**

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

##  **If You Wish to be Removed from our Database:**

At any point you may ask that we remove your information from our systems. Please contact Jocelyn at insidebrucrewlife@gmail.com with your request, and we will do that immediately.

The same applies for what information we hold about you and can be identified as being about you.

##  **Your Acceptance of these Terms:**

By using this Site, you signify your acceptance of this policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our Site. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of changes to this policy will be deemed your acceptance of those changes.

##  **DISCLOSURE FOR MY READERS**

This policy is valid from May 2, 2018.

This blog is a personal blog written and edited by me. For questions about this blog, please contact  Jocelyn at insidebrucrewlife@gmail.com

This blog accepts forms of cash advertising, sponsorship, and other forms of compensation.

This blog abides by word of mouth marketing standards. We believe in honesty of relationship, opinion and identity. The compensation received may influence the advertising content, topics or posts made in this blog. That content, advertising space or post will be clearly identified as paid or sponsored content.

Inside BruCrew Life may be compensated to provide opinion on products, services, websites and various other topics. Even though Inside BruCrew Life receives compensation for our posts or advertisements, we will always give our honest opinions, findings, beliefs, or experiences on those topics or products. The views and opinions expressed on this blog are purely the bloggers’ own. Any product claim, statistic, quote, or other representation about a product or service should be verified with the manufacturer, provider or party in question.

This blog does not contain any content which might present a conflict of interest.

To get your own policy, go to http://www.disclosurepolicy.org
